http://www.dsl.ac.uk/privacy

About Scots
What is Scots?
A language or a dialect?
About Scots
What is Scots?
A language or a dialect?
Privacy PolicyIntroduction
Scottish Language Dictionaries is Scotland’s lexicographical body for the Scots Language. We are committed to respecting and protecting your personal data. This statement explains why we collect your personal data and how we use it.
Scottish Language Dictionaries asks its Friends (formerly Members) and other supporters to “opt-in” for marketing communications such as e-newsletters. You can decide not to receive communications from us at any time. If you wish to opt out, please contact us by emailing info@dsl.ac.uk, call us on 0131 220 1294 or write to Scottish Language Dictionaries, 9 Coates Crescent, Edinburgh EH3 7AL.
We will never sell your personal data, nor will we share it with anyone else,
except as detailed in ‘Sharing Data’ below.
1. About us
2. Information We Collect and How We Use It
3. How We Protect and Store Your Data
4. Keeping You In Control
5. Cookies
6. Changes to Our Privacy Policy
1. About Us
Your personal data (i.e. any information which identifies you, or which can be identified as relating to you personally) will be collected and used by Scottish Language Dictionaries, a charity registered in Scotland with charity registration number SC032910. We are based at 9 Coates Crescent, Edinburgh EH3 7AL. You can call us on 0131 220 1294 or email us at info@dsl.ac.uk.
2. Information We Collect and How We Use It
Personal data you provide
We ask you to “opt-in” for marketing communications, such as e-newsletters, and use the personal data you give us with your consent for this purpose.
When you sign up for communications or donate to us, we will collect the information you give us which may include:
• personal details (for example name, email address) when you register for e-newsletters
• information on preferences and interests (e.g. whether you are an educator, writer or publisher) so that we know what information you are mostly likely to be interested in.
If you decide to donate to us, e.g. through subscription, word sponsorship, or gift, we will keep records of when and how much you give and whether it relates to a specific cause or campaign. (If you use a credit card to donate through a site such as Just Giving, your card details are not shared with us.)
You can decide to stop receiving communications from us at any time. If you wish to do so please email us at info@dsl.ac.uk to unsubscribe.
How We Use This Data
We use the personal data you have consented to give given us to promote the work of Scottish Language Dictionaries and to suggest ways to support our work. This includes:
• sending you e-newsletters you have opted to receive
• administering donations (e.g. throughannual subscriptions, word sponsorships, and gifts) or supporting your and fundraising activities, including processing Gift Aid;
• helping us respect your choices and preferences (e.g. if you ask not to receive marketing material, we’ll keep a record of this).
When you receive a communication from us, we may collect information about how you respond to or interact with that communication, and this may affect how we communicate with you in future.
We may carry out research and analysis on our subscribers and supporters to determine the success of campaigns, better understand behaviour and responses and identify patterns and trends. This helps inform our approach towards our communications and makes Scottish Language Dictionaries a stronger and more effective organisation.
We will only use and store information for as long as it is needed for the purposes it was collected for. If you have opted in to receive our e-newsletter(s), we will keep your information until you opt out. If you ask us not to send you e-newsletters by email , we will stop using your email address for this purpose and we’ll keep a record of your preference not to be emailed. We continually review what information we hold and delete what is no longer required.
Fundraising
As a charity, we rely on donations and support from others to continue our vital work. From time to time, we may contact our Friends and supporters with suggestions of ways to support our work. This might be about a campaign, an activity or competition we’re running, or to suggest ways you can raise funds on our behalf.
We’ll only include messages on how to support us if you’ve opted-in to receive an e-newsletter from us or if you have previously taken part in a fundraising campaign. You can, of course, unsubscribe at any time.
Sharing Data
We will never sell your personal data.
We may share personal data with subcontractors or suppliers who provide us with services. Examples include MailChimp for email management services, SurveyMonkey for evaluation and feedback, and EventBrite for event management.
Occasionally, where we partner with other organisations, we may also share information with them (for example, if you register to attend an event being jointly organised by us and another charity or one of the Scottish Universities). We’ll only share information when necessary to provide the service you have signed up for and we’ll make sure to notify you first.
3. How We Protect and Store Your Data
We use a variety of physical and technical measures to keep your data safe and to prevent unauthorised access to, or use or disclosure of your personal information.
Electronic data and databases are stored on secure computer systems and we control who has access to information (using both physical and electronic means). Our staff receive data protection training and we have a set of data protection procedures which staff are required to follow when handling personal data.
Where we store information
Scottish Language Dictionaries is based in Scotland and we store our data within the European Union. Some organisations which provide services to us may transfer personal data outside of the EEA, but we’ll only allow them to do this if your data is adequately protected.
For example, we use MailChimp to manage our email distribution. MailChimp subscribes to the EU-US Privacy Shield regime.
4. Keeping You In Control
We want to ensure you remain in control of your personal data. Part of this is making sure you understand your legal rights, which are as follows:
• the right to confirmation as to whether or not we have your personal data and, if we do, to obtain a copy of the personal information we hold (this is known as a subject access request)
• the right to have your data erased (though this will not apply where it is necessary for us to continue to use the data for a lawful reason)
• the right to have inaccurate data corrected
• the right to object to your data being used for marketing or profiling
Any questions you have in relation to this policy or how we use your personal data should be sent to info@dsl.ac.uk or addressed to our Chief Executive, Scottish Language Dictionaries, 9 Coates Crescent, Edinburgh EH3 7AL .
If you want to access your information, or if you have any questions in relation to this policy or how we use your personal data, please email info@dsl.ac.uk or write to our Chief Executive, Scottish Language Dictionaries, 9 Coates Crescent, Edinburgh EH3 7AL.
Complaints
You can complain about an issue concerning your data protection and privacy rights to Scottish Language Dictionaries directly by contacting our Chief Executive using the details above.
If you are not happy with our response, or you believe that your data protection or privacy rights have been infringed, you can complain to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office which regulates and enforces data protection law in the UK.
Details of how to do this can be found at https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/raising-concerns or you can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office directly at https://ico.org.uk/concerns or telephone 0303 123 1113.
5. Cookies and Links to Other Sites
Cookies
This website uses cookies. Cookies are pieces of data, normally stored in text files that websites place on visitors’ computers to store information about the visitor or the device they’re using.
This information is used to make the site work as you expect it to. The information collected cannot personally identify you, but is used to personalise your time on our website.
Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics to collect information on browsing. Google Analytics uses cookies to tell us how many people visit the site, what pages they’re reading and the types of browsers and devices they use to visit the site. All of the information that is collected is anonymised and cannot be used to identify you.
Deleting cookies
You can delete cookies from your browser at any time. About Cookies gives advice on how you can delete the cookies stored by your browser. Please note that this link takes you off our website.
Links to other sites
Our website may contain hyperlinks to other websites. We are not responsible for the content or functionality of any of those external websites (but please let us know if a link is not working by emailing us at info@dsl.ac.uk.
6. Changes to Our Privacy Policy
We will amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to ensure it remains up to date and accurately reflects how and why we use your personal data. The current version of our Privacy Policy will always be posted on our website.
Top
Copyright
| Privacy Policy
Contact us
Website hosted by theUniversity of Glasgow
Supported by theScottish Government
Scottish Language Dictionaries LtdWe are a Scottish Company (SC230070)and Charity (SC032910)
